Finding Aid for Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra Association records, 1957-1983
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra Association records 1957-1983
Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra Association.
2.5 linear feet
89159 Bp.5 2
Organization formed to support and assist the Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra, Mount Clemens, Michigan, by means of fund raising activities and ticket sales promotions. Bylaws and board of directors minutes; also records of auxiliary organizations, the Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra Women's Association and the Mount Clemens Symphony League; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by the Macomb County Historical Society through Betty Lou Morris and Mrs. W. Whitney Sawyer, President of the Historical Society (Donor No. 7610 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra was formed in the Spring of 1956, primarily through the efforts of John Sweeney, who became the Orchestra's first conductor. The first concert was held January 26, 1957.
In 1958, the Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra Association (MCSOA) was formed to augment ticket sales, host receptions and assist with operating needs. Adjunct groups grew out of this initial Association to help with other areas. Among these other auxiliary groups were the Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra Women's Association (MCSOWA), formed in 1966, and the Mount Clemens Symphony League, formed in 1978. These organizations held fund-raising activities and promoted the Orchestra and music appreciation to the community.
The Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra Women's Association was a member of the Michigan Orchestra Women's Association (MOWA). MOWA was organized in 1955 as a means of mutual support and communication among women's associations for symphony orchestras in Michigan. It was the first such association of its kind in the country.
Declining concert attendance and slipping community support led to the disbanding of the MCSOA and its auxiliaries throughout the early 1980s. The Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra was disbanded in 1983.
The Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra Association records consist of approximately two and one-half linear feet of minutes, financial reports, printed materials, bylaws, clippings and photographs. The records are those of the Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra Association and its related organizations, the Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra Women's Association, Michigan Orchestra Women's Association, and the Mount Clemens Symphony League. These are primarily minutes and reports.
The majority of the record covers the time period from the mid 1970s to the Orchestra's disbanding in 1983. The newspaper clippings and printed materials sections span from the Orchestra's creation in 1956 to its demise in 1983. Included in these sections are materials relating to the Orchestra as well as the various supporting associations.
Subjects:
Mount Clemens (Mich.); Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra Association.; Music--Michigan--Mount Clemens.; Symphony orchestras--Michigan--Mount Clemens.; Women--Michigan--Mount Clemens--Societies and clubs.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ballet.; Costumes.; Mount Clemens Symphony Orchestra Association.; Music--Michigan--Mount Clemens.; Orchestras.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Organizational Records, 1957-1983
  - Bylaws and Board of Director's Minutes
    - 1976-1978 (Box 1)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Women's Association Constitution, Minutes and Treasury Reports, 1974-1978 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Orchestra Women's Association Minutes and Reports, 1974-1978 (Box 1)
  - Symphony League Minutes and Financial Reports, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - Clippings
    - 1959, 1966-1970 (Box 1)
    - 1971-1977 (Box 1)
    - 1965-1983 (Box 1)
  - Printed Materials 1957-1983 (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
- Other records
  - Minutes, correspondence, performance information (Box 2)
    (unprocessed)
  - Financial and printed (Box 3)